<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-13T05:04:22+00:00</updated><id>https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/feed.xml</id><title type="html">KAIST Climate System Lab</title><subtitle>Understanding Earth&apos;s climate system through interdisciplinary research, advanced modeling, and data analysis. Led by Prof. Jin-Soo Kim at KAIST.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Fire-Climate Interactions in Southeastern Siberia</title><link href="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/06/10/fire-climate-study.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fire-Climate Interactions in Southeastern Siberia" /><published>2024-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T05:01:32+00:00</updated><id>https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/06/10/fire-climate-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/06/10/fire-climate-study.html"><![CDATA[<p>Our latest study on fire-climate interactions reveals fascinating connections between snow melting patterns and large-scale fire activity in southeastern Siberia. This research demonstrates how regional climate conditions directly influence fire behavior and spread.</p>

<h2 id="research-highlights">Research Highlights</h2>

<p>We discovered that earlier snow melting in spring creates conditions that significantly increase fire activity later in the season. This finding has important implications for:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Fire management strategies</strong> in boreal regions</li>
  <li><strong>Carbon emissions</strong> from wildfires</li>
  <li><strong>Ecosystem dynamics</strong> under changing climate</li>
  <li><strong>Regional climate feedbacks</strong> from fire activity</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="methodology">Methodology</h2>

<p>Our approach combines:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Satellite observations of snow cover and fire activity</li>
  <li>Regional climate modeling</li>
  <li>Statistical analysis of temperature and precipitation patterns</li>
  <li>Integration with global Earth system models</li>
</ul>

<p>This interdisciplinary approach allows us to understand fire-climate interactions at multiple scales, from local weather patterns to global climate systems.</p>]]></content><author><name>jin-soo-kim</name></author><category term="research" /><category term="fire dynamics" /><category term="siberia" /><category term="climate change" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest study on fire-climate interactions reveals fascinating connections between snow melting patterns and large-scale fire activity in southeastern Siberia. This research demonstrates how regional climate conditions directly influence fire behavior and spread. Research Highlights We discovered that earlier snow melting in spring creates conditions that significantly increase fire activity later in the season. This finding has important implications for: Fire management strategies in boreal regions Carbon emissions from wildfires Ecosystem dynamics under changing climate Regional climate feedbacks from fire activity Methodology Our approach combines: Satellite observations of snow cover and fire activity Regional climate modeling Statistical analysis of temperature and precipitation patterns Integration with global Earth system models This interdisciplinary approach allows us to understand fire-climate interactions at multiple scales, from local weather patterns to global climate systems.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Insights into Carbon-Climate Feedback Mechanisms</title><link href="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/03/20/carbon-research.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Insights into Carbon-Climate Feedback Mechanisms" /><published>2024-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T05:01:32+00:00</updated><id>https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/03/20/carbon-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/03/20/carbon-research.html"><![CDATA[<p>Our recent research into carbon-climate feedback mechanisms reveals important insights about future carbon sequestration capacity. As we work toward carbon neutrality by 2050, understanding how land and ocean systems will respond to changing climate conditions becomes increasingly critical.</p>

<h2 id="key-findings">Key Findings</h2>

<p>Current data shows that land and ocean systems absorb approximately 50% of global carbon emissions. However, our models suggest that this absorption capacity may change significantly under future climate scenarios.</p>

<p>Our integrated Earth system models help us understand:</p>
<ul>
  <li>How warming temperatures affect soil carbon storage</li>
  <li>Ocean acidification impacts on marine carbon uptake</li>
  <li>Vegetation responses to changing precipitation patterns</li>
  <li>Feedback loops between carbon storage and climate change</li>
</ul>

<p>This research contributes to more accurate climate projections and informs policy decisions for achieving global climate goals.</p>]]></content><author><name>jin-soo-kim</name></author><category term="research" /><category term="carbon cycle" /><category term="climate modeling" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our recent research into carbon-climate feedback mechanisms reveals important insights about future carbon sequestration capacity. As we work toward carbon neutrality by 2050, understanding how land and ocean systems will respond to changing climate conditions becomes increasingly critical. Key Findings Current data shows that land and ocean systems absorb approximately 50% of global carbon emissions. However, our models suggest that this absorption capacity may change significantly under future climate scenarios. Our integrated Earth system models help us understand: How warming temperatures affect soil carbon storage Ocean acidification impacts on marine carbon uptake Vegetation responses to changing precipitation patterns Feedback loops between carbon storage and climate change This research contributes to more accurate climate projections and informs policy decisions for achieving global climate goals.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KAIST Climate System Lab Launch</title><link href="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/01/15/lab-launch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KAIST Climate System Lab Launch" /><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T05:01:32+00:00</updated><id>https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/01/15/lab-launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sangdon-park.github.io/lab-website-example1/2024/01/15/lab-launch.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce the launch of the KAIST Climate System Lab! Our interdisciplinary research group focuses on understanding the complex interactions within Earth’s climate system through advanced modeling and data analysis.</p>

<p>Our lab addresses one of the greatest challenges facing humanity - climate change. We combine expertise in climate science, Earth system modeling, and environmental analysis to develop innovative solutions for climate adaptation and mitigation.</p>

<h2 id="research-focus">Research Focus</h2>

<p>Our research spans four main areas:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Climate System Science</strong>: Exploring interactions between Earth’s atmosphere, land, and ocean systems</li>
  <li><strong>Earth System Modeling</strong>: Developing integrated models to predict future climate states</li>
  <li><strong>Carbon-Climate Feedback</strong>: Understanding how climate change impacts global carbon cycles</li>
  <li><strong>Fire-Climate Interactions</strong>: Analyzing fire dynamics under changing atmospheric conditions</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="join-our-team">Join Our Team</h2>

<p>We welcome passionate researchers at all levels - undergraduate interns, graduate students, and postdoctoral researchers. If you’re interested in contributing to cutting-edge climate research, please contact Prof. Jin-Soo Kim at jinddu@gmail.com.</p>]]></content><author><name>jin-soo-kim</name></author><category term="lab news" /><category term="research" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the launch of the KAIST Climate System Lab! Our interdisciplinary research group focuses on understanding the complex interactions within Earth’s climate system through advanced modeling and data analysis. Our lab addresses one of the greatest challenges facing humanity - climate change. We combine expertise in climate science, Earth system modeling, and environmental analysis to develop innovative solutions for climate adaptation and mitigation. Research Focus Our research spans four main areas: Climate System Science: Exploring interactions between Earth’s atmosphere, land, and ocean systems Earth System Modeling: Developing integrated models to predict future climate states Carbon-Climate Feedback: Understanding how climate change impacts global carbon cycles Fire-Climate Interactions: Analyzing fire dynamics under changing atmospheric conditions Join Our Team We welcome passionate researchers at all levels - undergraduate interns, graduate students, and postdoctoral researchers. If you’re interested in contributing to cutting-edge climate research, please contact Prof. Jin-Soo Kim at jinddu@gmail.com.]]></summary></entry></feed>